Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/sonyanadesan (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

C#

Angular

SQL

Honors-Awards

Vote of Thanks

Shortlisted in the Future Stars of Tech - Developer Category
Q2 2020 Quarterly Rockstar

Sonya Nadesan

Software Engineer at Jefferies | Treasury Technology London, England, United Kingdom

Summary

I am a hard-working and passionate Software Engineer with over five years' commercial experience, currently working for an investment bank, Jefferies. Since graduating with a BSc (Hons) First Class in Software Engineering from Kingston University, I have worked for several companies, allowing me to explore organizations of varying size, industry, culture and technologies. Throughout my career, my work has been recognised through various means being shortlisted in the Future Stars of Tech, being recognised in our Quarterly Rockstars during my time at Mimecast, and more recently, being promoted, here, at Jefferies. Currently, I am involved in the development of web applications (full stack), Windows services and Power BI reports, whilst expanding my knowledge of the banking world. I am heavily involved in mentoring and training new joiners and further contribute to the culture at Jefferies as an active member of ERGs, which aligns well with my interest in volunteering – raising awareness, participating in research, donating and supporting campaigns. I am a proud supporter of Cancer Research UK and British Heart Foundation.

Experience

Jefferies

4 years

Associate Software Engineer

December 2023 - Present (1 year 7 months)

Bishopsgate London | Industry: Investment Banking | Team: Treasury | Received Promotion | Hybrid

Development

- Development of greenfield web application in .NET 8, EF Core, Angular, RxJS and DevExtreme
- Contributed in the design decisions on the technologies and approaches to be used

- Studied the architecture (internal/external/vendor applications, databases, MQs, SFTPs & DBs)
- Contributed to application remediation performing major upgrades and fixing SSL issues
- Gained experience with testing frameworks including xUnit, Moq, Reqnroll (Specflow) and Gherkin
- Developed robust Windows Services to communicate data between applications
- · Heavily involved in designing screen layouts with user experience in mind
- Refactored code responsible for payment netting, modification and approval workflow
- Involved in the migration from Swift MT (ISO15022) to Swift MX (ISO20022)
- Developed Power BI visualisations and working knowledge of DAX theory and writing formulae

Other Responsibilities

- Good knowledge of Bamboo's hierarchy and the role of servers, BitBucket, agents, JFrog and IIS
- Investigate issues in our new CI/CD pipeline to support the "Build Once, Deploy Anywhere" process
- Provide production-line support to prevent the firm from having to face penalty charges on delays
- Developed knowledge of the trade life cycle: execution, matching, booking, settlement, post-trade
- Awareness of the various markets: Forex, Equities, Fixed Income, Derivatives and Repo (Collateral)
- Awareness of the role of the Swift Network, Swift Message Types and their uses
- Represented Treasury Technology in networking events to advertise the Internship Programme
- Mentoring graduates and training new joiners explaining technical concepts, goal setting
- Active member of ERG, J-Able (rebranding, events, raising awareness and fundraising)
- Familiar with RedGate, WinSCP, IBM MQ Explorer, GitHub Co-Pilot, Power BI and DAX Editor
- Follow Scrum methodology participating in daily stand ups, sprint planning and design meetings

Analyst Software Engineer

July 2021 - November 2023 (2 years 5 months)

Bishopsgate, London | Industry: Investment Banking | Team: Treasury • Remote; Hybrid since Nov 2021

GTMS Portal - JefCast

- Front-end development of complex, reusable components in Angular, saving development time
- Extended functionality of components provided by third-party UI component library, DevExtreme
- Developed features that were compatible with both data grids and pivot grids
- Developed features displaying updates in real-time using web socket technologies such as SignalR
- Developed Web APIs and back-end services in .NET Core, C# and MS SQL Server

Other Responsibilities

- Mentoring interns/grads explaining technical concepts, helping them debug code/fix Git issues
- Presented projects to tech teams across the firm covering background and technical overview
- Involved in providing code reviews, testing, deploying and releasing to both QA and production
- Produced Wiki pages on reusable code written in .NET and Angular via Confluence
- Currently learning cloud computing using Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Participated in events organised by various employee resource groups across the firm
- Working knowledge of the domain: brokers, securities, cash usage, settlements and trading
- Familiar with tools such as VS, VS Code, Jira, GitBash, Dev Tools, Event Viewer, Bamboo and IIS

Mimecast

.NET Developer

May 2020 - July 2021 (1 year 3 months)

Broadgate, London | Industry: Cybersecurity | Team: Marketing

- Developed features and programs in C#, ASP.NET MVC and EpiServer
- Participated in code reviews and deployed code to test and live environments
- Took ownership of redeveloping features to improve maintainability, testability and efficiency

- Took ownership in developing code to alter the hierarchy of pages in EpiServer for SEO
- Improved page load time by writing code to enable lazy-loading of all images defined in the CMS
- Developed various advanced find and replace tools for EpiServer using reflection
- Actively participated in meetings, suggesting ways to improve how we deliver as a team
- Helped fellow developers by explaining various technical concepts clean code, EpiServer etc.
- Involved in recruitment writing job descriptions, reviewing CVs and interviewing candidates
- Initially a contract role under LMA Recruitment; offered the permanent role in November 2020
- Work was recognised by Senior Management in Mimecast's Global Marketing Q2 Rockstars
- Confident in version control via the UNIX shell using the command language, Bash
- Familiar with tools including Visual Studio, GitHub, Jira, Slack, Dev Tools, Azure DevOps

Marie Curie UK

Junior .NET Developer

February 2019 - March 2020 (1 year 2 months)

Vauxhall, London | Industry: Non-Profit | Team: Marketing • On-site (remote as of March 2020)

- Worked on several web applications written in C#, .NET Framework, MVC and JavaScript
- Good knowledge of various software Design Patterns and SOLID Principles
- Good knowledge of Entity Framework (code-first, database-first, graphs and states) and LINQ
- Good knowledge of CMS development using EpiServer which was used for the main site
- Considered data requirements when making changes to the database design for new features
- Gained experience in authentication using ASP.NET Identity and awareness of security issues
- Worked in a Scrum team attended stand-ups, retro, sprint planning and backlog grooming

• Familiar with Visual Studio, GitHub, Fiddler, Slack, Jira, Trello, ClubHouse and Azure DevOps

I decided to leave after being offered three jobs but due to the pandemic and lockdown, the accepted offer was pulled a couple of days before the agreed start date. I started interviewing virtually for a month and was offered four more jobs, giving me plenty of options in who I wanted to work for next!

GenSight

Graduate Developer

July 2017 - February 2019 (1 year 8 months)

Hampton, Greater London, United Kingdom | Industry: Portfolio Management | Team: Product

- Took full ownership of the development of financial tools using MS Excel and VBA
- Tools were developed for high-profile clients including Johnson & Johnson, GSK and Pfizer
- Heavily involved in writing test cases and unit tests for the complex and reusable macros I wrote
- Optimized performance of VBA macros from 20 mins to under 10 seconds
- Touched on web development in VB.NET (webforms), JavaScript and AJAX
- Familiar with tools including Visual Studio, Git (using Azure DevOps) and Dev Tools
- Involved in organising Christmas events including Secret Santa and Charity Fundraising.

Kingston University Teaching Assistant September 2016 - April 2017 (8 months)

London, United Kingdom

- Provided support to first-year and second-year students during lab sessions
- Provided support for two modules Programming and Databases

Kingston University
Academic Mentor
September 2015 - June 2016 (10 months)
London, United Kingdom

- Arranged regular one-to-one and group sessions both online and oncampus to first-year students
- Explained technical concepts and set challenges to help students consolidate their knowledge/skills

- Advertised the mentoring scheme to courses across the university at various showcase events
- Identified students with special needs and provided flexible sessions to cater for individual needs
- Directed students to services to support their needs from SEN assessments to financial support

Education

Kingston University

BSc(Hons), Software Engineering · (September 2014 - July 2017)

Wallington High School for Girls

Grammar School · (September 2010 - June 2014)

Old Palace Of John Whitgift

Independent School · (January 2010 - July 2010)

Norbury Manor Business & Enterprise College

Comprehensive School · (September 2007 - December 2009)